<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<event>


	<speakers>
		<fname>Tonye</fname>
		<lname>Cole</lname>
		<bio>Tonye Patrick Cole is the Co-Founder and Group Executive Director of #sahara, which is an energy conglomerate with a strong operating presence spanning the entire energy value chain in Nigeria to neighboring West African countries and past the African sphere to Europe, Asia and the Middle East. The global operations of the Sahara Group comprises of 19 operating companies with over 650 employees located in over six countries. Mr. Cole and his partners have strategically managed the operating companies from incubation and have successfully driven the company to an USD11billion annual revenue base. Tonye Cole is chiefly responsible for the strategic expansion of businesses within the organization’s energy portfolio and is actively involved in the exploration of the upstream businesses in new frontier and emerging markets.
#br#br
In addition to founding and managing one of Nigeria's largest energy conglomerates, he is also the founder of the Nehemiah Youth Empowerment Initiative, which is an NGO set up to empower the Nigerian youths in different parts of the country. Consequently, he is a "Brand Ambassador" for Nigeria, working to inspire youth to unlock the continent's tremendous human potential. This is achieved by working closely with a good number of foundations in Nigeria (Africa 2.0, Rise Youth Foundation, Down
Syndrome Foundation, Servant Leaders Foundation, Compassion Center for Physically Handicapped Children in Port Harcourt, Cheshire Home for the Disabled in Lagos, Slum2School Project and various charitable organizations).
#br#br
Tonye Cole has delivered numerous papers on diverse topics such as Oil and Gas Dynamics, Sustainable Energy, Youth Empowerment, Entrepreneurship and Capacity‐Building, Leadership, Change, Strategy, among others. He has also participated actively in various seminars, trainings and conferences till date.
#br#br
Mr Cole attended the University of Lagos where he gained his merit Honors in Architecture.
#br
Mr. Cole is happily married with 3 beautiful kids.
</bio>
	</speakers>
	
	
	<speakers>
		<fname>Zainab</fname>
		<lname>Shinkafi-Bagudu</lname>
		<bio>Dr. Zainab Shinkafi-Bagudu is a mother, wife, Paediatric Consultant and child’s right advocate and anti cancer campaigner. After her graduating from Queens College Lagos, she obtained an MBBS from the Ahmadu Bello University Zaria. Her specialist training in Peadiatrics in the United Kingdom lasted 7years after which she returned to Nigeria to set up and head the Paediatric Unit of Garki Hospital under a new PPP scheme with the FCT. In 2009, she set up a trail blazing diagnostic centre #medicaid.
	#br#br
	She has become a loud voice in the fight against cancers in Nigeria particularly breast and cervical cancers and serves as a role model for women in particular in the Northern parts. Her foundation, the Medicaid Cancer foundation sponsors campaigns to prevent, treat and diagnose these cancers across the country.#br#br
	As well as being chief executive of Medicaid, Dr Shinkafi-Bagudu is currently serving on the ministerial committee to build world class diagnostic centres in Nigeria and is a mentor on the You-Win project.
	</bio>
	</speakers>


	<speakers>
		<fname>Kunle</fname>
		<lname>Soyiran</lname>
		<bio>Olakunle Soriyan is the Principal Transformation Strategist of the #kunleweb, a Total Life Management (TLM) and Nation Building, Training, Coaching and Consulting Firm. The company works with leaders of various arms of Government and NGO's as well as Business and Institutional leaders at all levels, using original, home grown research and principle based methodologies. Soriyan serves on the Board of various organisations, and is a daily radio host, Philosopher, Trainer and Consultant of high pedigree.#br#br He has developed many best-selling products helping hundreds of thousands of individuals across the globe. The Personal Advisor, Counsellor, Coach and Confidant to many high net-worth individuals and high-profile organisations, promotes ORIGINALITY as a critical pathway to PURPOSEFULNESS at any level of development. He is happily married to his immensely gifted Wife, Tiwalade and they are blessed with a wise son, Olakunle David.#br#br</bio>
	</speakers>
	
	
	<speakers>
		<fname>Tonye</fname>
		<lname>Princewill</lname>
		<bio>Prince Tonye Princewill, fondly called 'TP' by friends, followers and political associates has acquired the enviable reputation as a different kind of politician; a cut above the rest of clamoring politicians who see politics as an end in itself rather than a means to offer service to the electorate. Many who know the Kalabari Prince or have had close dealings with him attest to the passion with which he pursues what he believes in. Due to his penchant for doing things differently, he has been dubbed the "digital" politician of our time.#br#br
A believer in the maxim that politics is too serious a business to be left to politicians, Prince Tonye Princewill was first brought into national limelight in 2007 when he contested for the governorship position of Rivers state, on the platform of the Action Congress of Nigeria (ACN) against Mr. Celestine Omehia, the People’s Democratic Party (PDP) candidate. After the highly spirited electoral battle, Mr. Celestine Omehia was declared the winner of the highly contentious election by the Independent National electoral Commission (INEC). #br#br
To protest against the injustice of his stolen mandate, Tonye Princewill challenged the declared victory of Mr Omehia in the Election tribunal and was on the path of victory when the Supreme Court overturned Omehia’s victory and declared Rotimi Chibuike Amaechi as the duly elected governor of Rivers state.
As a highly principled politician who puts his people’s interest over and above his quest for political office, Princewill dropped the legal challenge against the People’s Democratic Party (PDP) and joined forces with Governor Rotimi Amaechi in the larger interest of the Rivers people. This he did with the full backing of the Action Congress (ACN) in Rivers state.  Following this principled position, Tonye Princewill later cast his lot for the People’s Democratic Party (PDP). He has since remained in the PDP, offering his advice to the Federal and Rivers state governments on issues concerning the people of Rivers state while also carrying out humanitarian causes on matters that are dear to him.
Prior to his foray into the political arena, Prince Tonye Princewill had made good as a successful businessman. Riverdrill Group of Companies (Nigeria), the company he founded and which he is Chairman is a private business concern with interests inOil and Gas, Information Technology, Environmental Waste, Aviation services and consulting, among other varied interests.#br#br
Tonye Princewill did not just set out to be a businessman, however! His early career was kick-startedwhen he started work as a Reservoir and Well-site Petroleum Engineer. Some other organizations where he cut his professional teeth include the UK's Oil and Gas Regulatory Agency, the Department of Trade and Industry (United Kingdom) where he worked as a Risk Analyst. He was at some point the Chief Technology Officer of Panasonic in the United Kingdom and also served at the Global Asset Management desk of Citibank.
To prepare him for the active political and private life that he leads, Prince Tonye Princewill, born in the UK to the royal family of King T. J. T. Princewill, theAmanyanabo of Kalabari Kingdom in Rivers State, a former Professor of Medical Microbiology before he became a monarch, hebegan his primary education in the United Kingdom. On returning to Nigeria with his parents, he continued his education at Hillcrest High School in Jos (1976-1980). He completed his High School education and obtained his West African Senior Certificate/General Certificate of Education at the Federal Government College (Port Harcourt) in 1985. He holds a BSc degree in Petroleum Engineering at the University of Port Harcourt and later acquired a Master's degree in Mineral Resources Engineering at the Imperial College London.Princewill also holds a PRINCE 2 Project Management Practitioner Certificate from the United Kingdom.#br#br
A dogged advocate for youth empowerment in Nigeria, Princewill has started several initiatives aimed at inspiring the youths andsteering them away from violence and militancy in the Niger Delta towards positive developments of their talents and leadership skills.In June 2012, for instance, Prince Tonye Princewill sponsored and led a 10-man delegation of Nigerian youths, under the aegis of Change Nigeria Group, to Dubai in the United Arab Emirate and Accra, Ghanafor acquisition of knowledge on entrepreneurship, governance, leadership and self-development.#br#br
In addition to his advocacy for youths, Tonye Princewill through his Princewill Trust engages in many humanitarian activities in aid of disadvantaged people and communities, especially in the Niger Delta. A recent humanitarian mission organized by Princewill Trust and personally led Prince TonyePrincewill was the relief work done to bring about relief and succor to several communities that were ravaged by flood in 2013.#br#br
As a result of Tonye Princewill’s sheer dynamism which is constantly on display in his result–oriented activities, be it in the public sector or his private endeavor, he has come under tremendous pressure to run again for the office of governor of River state. Concerned deeply about the current condition of his Rivers state people, Princewill is consulting with his associates and constituents before making a concrete pronouncement on his political future.
A well-grounded family man, Tonye Princewill is husband to Rosemary and father to a delightful daughter and a lovely set of twin boys.
</bio>
	</speakers>
	
	
	<speakers>
		<fname>Bankole</fname>
		<lname>Williams</lname>
		<bio>He is a UK Certified Life Coach and an Employee Engagement Expert . He is the author of &quot;Engaged to a job I hate&quot;; a book on career advancement and employee engagement. He was awarded Nigerian Author of the Year at the recently concluded Yada Magazine 2012 Readers Choice awards.#br#br
He is an emergent force to be reckoned with in the field of Management Consulting with over 7 years experience in Human Resources and consulting fields.#br
In his quest to understand and optimize human potential, Bankole has gained invaluable management and career experience, first at Guaranty Trust Bank, where he was an invaluable member of the Human Resources Team.#br#br
While at Guaranty Trust bank, he discovered his passion for workforce activation and man power development which led to his move to the Training department where he also facilitated trainings for staff in the bank, after which, he joined a reputable consulting firm, Visible Impact.#br#br
Due to his passion for proffering solutions to corporations and his vast consulting &amp; training experience, Bankole now serves as a Senior Partner and Management Consultant in EdgeEcution Consulting.#br#br
Bankole Williams has designed, managed and facilitated several customer service and personal mastery training programmes, management and leadership retreats for several organizations. He is an expert at delivering training solutions on product lines such as Self Mastery, Effective Communication, Team bonding, Superior service delivery, Leadership , Selling skills, Workforce Activation etc.#br#br
His facilitation skills are no doubt prolific, as he currently provides consulting interventions for banks and different organizations, some of which include, Guaranty Trust Bank, Access bank, Diamond Bank, Skye Bank, Stanbic IBTC, StanbicIBTC pensions, Fidelity bank, NLNG, UTC to mention a few.#br#br
In 2010, Bankole Williams co – led a Culture Transformation project for the Management of Ashaka Cement (AshakaCem) during which he was also given the sole responsibility of preparing the Organization Diagnostic Report for the Executive Management of Ashaka Cement. In December 2010, he co – led a one day highly successful Team Building retreat for the Management and over 600 staff of MultiChoice Nigeria.#br#br
He is a Host on the &quot;Market Place&quot; on Smooth 98.1fm. A radio programme aimed at empowering business people with the skills necessary to successfully run their businesses#br#br
Mr. Williams is a convener of Youth conferences and the Assistant Coordinator , Youth With a Purpose (YWAP), a nongovernmental organization where he speaks on a weekly basis, inspiring young people to become great achievers in Nigeria. YWAP’s vision is to positively affect the lives of Nigerian youth and he successfully motivates the youth to achieve this objective. He also empowers graduates at the After School Graduates Development Centre(AGDC) with speeches on Employability skills and Enterprise Development
Bankole’s greatest craving is to speak and cause people to discover and optimize their God given potential.</bio>
	</speakers>	
	
	<speakers>
		<fname>Ruth</fname>
		<lname>Obih</lname>
		<bio>Ruth is a trained lawyer and was &quot;Called to Bar&quot; in 2004 by the Supreme court of Nigeria. She went on to practice law at Ajumogobia &amp; Okeke, where she acquired an in-depth knowledge in the practice and application of law.#br#br
Her first attempt at entreprenuership was a fashion venture, which she had been operating from her university days. This led her to attend London College of fashion in 2006 so as to enhance her output. Whilst at Fashion College, she took short courses in fashion designing and merchandising. At the completion of those courses, she officially started the Clothing label &quot;ruru&quot; which was registered under Strawberry and co in 2005. Family pressure prompting her not to abandon law for fashion made Ruth turn her attention to law again. This time she proceeded to BPP law school UK to write the qualified lawyer transfer test (QLTT) and followed this up with internship training at a conveyancing law firm in 2006. This was when she discovered her interest in real Estate.#br#br
On Completing her training, she co-founded 3INVEST LTD, UK, a property consulting company, before returning to Nigeria in 2007 to establish 3INVEST Ltd. Ruth accessed the sector by introducing innovative services under her 3INVEST platform and over time, overcame the hurdles on the journey to establishing a reputable brand in a male dominated and red-tapped sector. #br#brIn 2011, 3INVEST became a registered Mark and Ruth went on to expand the scope of her involvement in the Real Estate sector by establishing a division focused on real estate advocacy and media management. Through this vision and its platforms, consumers, investors and real estate players have been empowered with useful and relevant information. 3INVEST is one of Africa's leading real estate brands with technology driven innovations that is changing the perception of real estate in Nigeria. From anchoring the first syndicated real estate show on radio "Real Estate On Air", publishing the most informative real estate information portal and convening the power brokers in the business for the annual Real Estate Unite Summit, 3INVEST has built a reputation in the sector as the go-to company for commercial real estate services in today's market.</bio>
	</speakers>
	
	<speakers>
		<fname>Kate</fname>
		<lname>Henshaw</lname>
		<bio>
		
Kate is one of the Most Talented Screen Personalities that deserves lots of accolades. She has contributed her own quota into the Entertainment Industry in Nigeria. She is one actress every good director would want to work with. Pretty and unpretentiously friendly, Kate Henshaw is one Nollywood personality who has worked herself to a level where she gets the sort of adulation that stars in Hollywood get.
Acting for the African screen diva, a trained medical microbiologist, began in Lagos in 1993 after a chance opportunity to audition for a role in the movie &quot;When the Sun Sets&quot;.
#br#br
She however started out as a model, advertising different products in calendars and shooting her first television commercial for Shield Deodorant in 1990. 
#br#br
She is not only one of the A list Star Actresses that every prominent producer looks out for, but she has also widened her horizon to the area of movie production. She was a co-producer of the remarkable and well scripted soap opera, CIRCLE OF THREE which was aired on Africa Independent Television, nationally and internationally.
#br#br
Kate is one of the few reputable screen personalities that have restored the lost glory of stage plays which used to dominate the theatre industry in the country of Nigeria.  She has been involved in numerous stage plays such as the internationally acclaimed Eve Ensler &quot;VAGINA MONOLOGUES&quot;, YORUBA ROMANCE, THE OTHER SIDE, NOT MY AFFAIR by Sefi Atta, THE WIVES, LITTLE DROPS by Ahmed Yerima and a live show tagged LOVING LAGOS at the Berlin Film Festival in 2009.
#br#br
Her Achievements/Awards
#ul
#li The Best Upcoming Actress in 1996 at the Afro-Hollywood Award, United Kingdom#lx
#li	Best upcoming actress 1996 at The Movie Awards (THEMA) organized by Fame Magazine#lx
#li Best Conduct Female(Actors Guild Awards 2004#lx
#li	Best Actress of the year award, Africa Movie Academy Awards (AMAA) 2008-2009#lx
#li	She was nominated for the Best International Drama in the New York Film Festival 2008 for her role in the film, RIVALS.#lx
#li	She is the first Nollywood Female Actress that would be invited to be part of the panel at the 2009 Berlin Film Festival along with Bollywood Super-Star, Shah Rukh Khan and German Top Actress, Maria Schrader.#lx
#li	Kate has been the Ambassador and Face of Onga Seasoning, a brand from Promasidor Nigeria Ltd for the past 5 years till date and she also hosts the cooking programme, ONGA TIME OUT#lx
#li	She is also the Ambassador for Samsung Mobile and Samsung Electronics.#lx
#li	Kate decided to support and lend her voice to a charity organization, Project Alert on Violence against Women and Children. This organization is on a journey to bring respect and love to all women and war against spousal abuse, child abuse, be it emotional, mental, physical or psychological. She is one of their Ambassadors.#lx
#li	She is currently expanding her brand into the global arena and her lifelong dream remains to build a charity foundation that will take destitute children off the streets, educate them and give them hope in the realest possible way.#lx
#li	She was made an EVANS Inspire Ambassador in 2008. Evans Publishing saw the need for a role model who could encourage the youth right from primary school.#lx
#li	An Ambassador for Golden Link for the National Cervical Cancer Prevention Programme#lx
#li	Nollywood Outstanding Personality Award on the 6th December 2009#lx
#li	Goodwill Ambassadors of the Nigeria Women Trust Fund on the 24th March 2011#lx
#li	The Billboard awards for Best Female Brand Ambassador#lx
#li	The Smile Widows Home Humanitarian Award.#lx
#ux
Kate Henshaw is very industrious, intelligent, humble and most of all has a God fearing and people loving personality. She has well over 260 films to her credit. She is one Actress that is still waxing strong in the Nigeria Movie Industry (aka NOLLYWOOD) and a role model to the young people in Africa.
		</bio>
	</speakers>
	
	<speakers>
		<fname>Maryam</fname>
		<lname>Uwais</lname>
		<bio>
		Mrs. Maryam Uwais MFR, is a practicing lawyer. She graduated with LL.B. (Hons) from the Ahmadu Bello University, Zaria and was subsequently called to Nigerian Bar. She later obtained an LLM from the same University in 1985. She is a member of the International Bar Association and an Associate Fellow, Institute for Islamic Banking &amp; Insurance, London, with a Post Graduate Diploma in Islamic Banking &amp; Insurance, London. 
		 #br#br
		Maryam Uwais has worked in several public sector namely, The Kano State Ministry of Justice, The Nigerian Law Reform Commission, The Central Bank of Nigeria and has served on several Federal, Regional and State Government Committees aimed at reforming identified challenges, including The Presidential Advisory Committee, the Northern Governors Committee on Reconciliation, Security and Healing and The Kano State Almajiri Committee. She currently practices law as the Principal Partner of #wali.
		 #br#br
		In addition to pursuing her career, she's the Founder and Chairperson of #iwei, a not-for-profit organization established in Kano State, Nigeria to empower and enable women and children attain their potential. 
		 #br#br
		Maryam Uwais has been and remains a Board Member of so many prestigious organisations, including The African Union Committee of Experts on the Rights and Welfare of the Child, The National Human Rights Commission (as Special Rapporteur on Child Rights), Women in Successful Careers, Justice Research Institute, LEAPAFRICA, the Coalition Against Tobacco, MUSAWA (Global Movement for Equity and Justice for the Muslim Woman) and currently serves as Vice Chair of the Nigeria Stability and Reconciliation Programme in Nigeria. She has served as Consultant to several programmes funded by the Open Society Initiative for West Africa, The World Bank, DFID, UNICEF and the British Council.
		 #br#br
		Maryam has delivered so many papers and articles relating to Economic, Social and Cultural Rights, Children's rights, Women's  rights, Prison reform, Constitutional and Electoral Reform, Interfaith dialogue.
		</bio> 
	</speakers>
	
	
	<speakers>
		<fname>Salamatu</fname>
		<lname>Suleiman</lname>
		<bio>
Mrs. Salamatu Suleiman is the ECOWAS Commissioner for Political Affairs, Peace and Security. She was born in Argungu in Kebbi State on October 27, 1960.  Her father was an Area Court Judge, while her mother came from the Gwandu royal family in Kebbi. As a Minister of Women Affairs, she succeeded in pumping life into gender and other women issues. She is an advocate of gender equality and decries marginalization of women in Nigerian politics. She championed the campaign that urged the States to give women at least 30% representation in elective and appointive positions. She is widely known for her advocacy for the education of the girl-child and decency in female appearances. A mentor to many young women, she often said that &quot;God has given women inherent capabilities, potential, capacities and it behoves them to explore those potentials and contribute to the home and nation&quot;. She participated in various public issues, private placement of shares, debt conversion as well as privatisation issues while working at the Continental Merchant Bank from 1989-1996. She demonstrates the qualities of a highly trusted leader: straight forwardness, respect, transparency, loyalty and many others. Little wonder her potentials came to limelight when she was elected the Vice President of Students Union, Ahmadu Bello University, Kongo Campus, Zaria between 1979 and 1980.#br#br
A member of the following:
#ul
#li International Bar Association #lx
#li Nigeria Bar Association #lx
#li LSE Alumni Association (Nigeria Branch) #lx
#li Federation of International D'Abogadas (FIDA) #lx
#li Institute of Directors (IOD) #lx
#ux
She is also the Founder of #alkali which was founded in 2007 to among other things act as a vehicle for helping people out of despair, eradication of poverty and generally assisting the less privileged members of the society to become self-reliant and contribute to national development. The Foundation achieves this through Adult literacy and Orphan sponsorship, Skills acquisition and women empowerment programmes, supporting the effort of Government in youth empowerment in the educational and agricultural sectors. 
		</bio> 
	</speakers>
	

</event>